Hi my name's Vicky,
مرحباً، اسمي "فيكي"،
and I'm one of the Content Developers here at Udacity.
وأنا مطورة محتوى هنا في Udacity.
We just finished learning about HTTP networking in JSON parsing.
انتهينا للتوّ من تعلّم ربط الشبكات بواسطة HTTP والتحليل بواسطة JSON.
We're now going to go through a food analogy to better
سنتناول الآن استعارة طعام مجازية
understand how all of these concepts fit together.
لنفهم بشكل أفضل كيفية عمل هذه المبادئ معاً.
Pretend you have a huge craving for pasta.
تخيّلوا أن لديكم رغبة عارمة لتناول المعكرونة.
So you're at your favorite pasta restaurant.
وأنتم جالسون في مطعم المعكرونة المفضّل لديكم.
You tell the waiter you want to order specifically the red sauce pasta dish.
تخبرون النادل بأنكم تريدون أن تطلبوا تحديداً طبق المعكرونة بالصلصة الحمراء.
This order information represents the address.
معلومة الطلب هذه تمثّل العنوان.
Now the waiter has your order information,
والآن، يملك النادل معلومة طلبكم،
which is equivalent to the address used to retrieve that information.
وهو ما يعادل العنوان الذي يُستخدم لاسترجاع تلك المعلومة.
The waiter then uses this information to go fetch your food in the main thread.
ثم يستخدم النادل هذه المعلومة لإحضار الطعام في السلسلة الرئيسية.
While the waiter is fetching your dish,
بينما يعمل النادل على إحضار الطبق،
you can do other stuff while waiting,
يمكنكم القيام بأشياء أخرى أثناء الانتظار،
such as drink water in the background thread.
مثل شرب الماء في السلسلة الثانوية.
Once you receive your pasta,
عندما تستلمون طبق المعكرونة،
you can now go through it,
يمكنكم الآن التعامل معه،
just like how you would go through that information from the main thread.
تماماً كما تتعاملون مع المعلومة من السلسلة الرئيسية.
In this case, the food order information represents the address,
في هذه الحالة، معلومة طلب الطعام تمثّل العنوان،
and the food represents JSON, which is the data.
والطعام يمثّل JSON، وهي البيانات.
The waiter retrieving your food is the process of
أما إحضار النادل للطعام فهو عملية ربط الشبكات بواسطة HTTP في السلسلة الثانوية،
while you continue to do things in the main thread.
بينما تستمرون أنتم بفعل أمور أخرى في السلسلة الرئيسية.
Lastly, going through your food is parsing JSON.
وأخيراً، أكل الطعام يمثّل التحليل بواسطة JSON.
Let's recap what we went through.
لنلخّص ما تحدثنا عنه.
When we request the pasta dish,
عندما نطلب طبق المعكرونة،
that represents the JSON data.
يمثّل ذلك بيانات JSON.
Communicating my request to the waiter and waiting for
إبلاغ النادل بالطلب
Going through my food and getting what I want is JSON parsing.
أكل الطعام وتلبية رغبتنا هو التحليل بواسطة JSON.